# My name is Candace. I write beautiful software.

I long for meaningful work that connects my heart to the world and those on my team. While I have many years of leadership experience, my current priorities are to grow personally and hone my technical skills. How can I help you?

## **Candace Camarillo**

**Phone** 

(503) 985-6082

**Email** 

candace.fox.camarillo@gmail.com

Website

candacefoxcamarillo.com

Education

The Art Institute of Portland

BS, Multimedia & Web Design - 2002 - 2006

Graduated with Honors and as Class Speaker

University of Oregon School of Music

Violin Performance Program - 1998 - 2001

### Skills

## **Technologies**

Full-Stack Languages

Engineering Python, Javascript, PHP, CSS, HTML, SASS

Architecture Design & UX

**AWS** 

Docker

Ops Flask, Django, Laravel, Vue, React, CakePHP, Yii, Zend,

Leadership Craft, Wordpress, Symfony

Microservices Data

CI/CD MySQL, Redis, Postgres, Neo4j, GraphQL, REST

# **Experience**

#### **Principal Software Engineer**

CMD Agency | January 2021 - present

Lead the full-stack technical direction and engineering effort of the GoGoSqueeZ.com rebuild. The success of the project led to the overhaul of their UK and Portugal properties. Technical direction of an internationalization service for Jeld-Wen's web properties. Used Vue.js to build

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Vacasa | April 2015 - March 2020

Lead the architecture and engineering of services central to the company's ability to scale. I generally focused on building smaller modern REST microservices to replace legacy monolithic business logic. I designed a long-term business logic migration plan, involving creation of an ORM "shim" between legacy business logic and long term technology objectives.

#### Senior Developer

Owen Jones & Partners | November 2013 - March 2015 Technical lead and developer on a variety of interactive projects, including web applications, mobile-friendly websites, and CMS integrations.

### Senior Software Developer, Interactive Developer

CMD Agency | November 2011 - November 2013 Lead and team engineer for full-stack web applications, mobile applications, microsites, and email campaigns. Working with front-end and back-end technologies such as Zend, Bootstrap, and MySQL.

### Designer, Developer, Owner

Candace Lapp Design, LLC | June 2006 - November 2011 Working directly with clients, I designed and developed projects ranging from business cards to full-stack web applications, motion graphics, and Flash applications.

#### Interactive Media Designer / Developer

Chamber Music Northwest | April 2005 - July 2006
Designed, engineered, and maintained this non-profit music organization's data-driven website. Worked with multiple stakeholders to produce a LAMP-stack application that managed artist profiles, concert schedules, music clips, a blog, and venue information.

#### Webmaster / User Support Assistant

University of Oregon Department of Public Safety October 1999 - December 2001

Designed, developed, and maintained this campus security department's website using front-end technologies. Provided IT assistance and user support.